Conservation is war
Virunga is a documentary, war film directed by Orlando von Einsiedel.
Virunga in the Democratic Republic of the Congo is Africa’s oldest national park, a UNESCO world heritage site, and a
contested ground among insurgencies seeking to topple the government that see untold profits in the land.
Among this ongoing power struggle, Virunga also happens to be the last
natural habitat for the critically endangered mountain gorilla.
The only thing standing in the way of the forces closing in around the gorillas: a handful of passionate park
rangers and journalists fighting to secure the park’s borders and expose the corruption of its enemies.
Filled with shocking footage, and anchored by the surprisingly deep and gentle characters of the gorillas themselves,
Virunga is a galvanizing call to action around an ongoing political and environmental crisis in the Congo.
Virunga is a 2014 British documentary film directed by Orlando von Einsiedel.
It focuses on the conservation work of park rangers within the Congo's Virunga National Park during the rise of the violent M23 Rebellion
in 2012 and investigates the activity of the British oil company Soco International within the UNESCO World Heritage Site.
Soco International ended up officially exploring oil
opportunities in Virunga in April 2014.
The film premiered at the Tribeca Film Festival on 17 April 2014.
After airing on Netflix, it was nominated for an
Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature.
The tone is thought_provoking.